<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<modDesc descVersion="106">
    <author>id577, Squallqt</author>
    <version>0.9.2.0</version>
    <title>
        <en>Advanced Damage System</en>
        <es>Sistema Avanzado De Daños</es>
		<pl>Zaawansowany system obrażeń</pl>
        <de>Erweitertes Schadenssystem</de>
        <fr>Système Avancé De Dégâts</fr>
        <it>Sistema Avanzato Di Danni</it>
        <ru>Продвинутая Система Повреждений</ru>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System adds a deep vehicle wear, failure, diagnostics, maintenance, and repair system to Farming Simulator 25. Instead of relying on a single generic condition value, each machine is built around multiple individual systems with their own condition, wear factors, stress accumulation, and risk of failure. Vehicle behaviour and the nature of breakdowns depend on operating conditions, load, temperature, and service quality.

The mod includes a temperature model for key systems, advanced battery and alternator simulation, realistic breakdown logic, expanded workshop workflows, service reports, maintenance history, and pre-shift inspections. As a result, vehicle management becomes a strategic part of gameplay: service takes time, poor operation increases the risk of failures, and neglecting machine condition can disrupt critical field work. A responsible farmer who looks after equipment, services it on time, and avoids unnecessary abuse will keep the fleet reliable and avoid serious problems during the season.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Rebalanced system wear factors
- "Quick Inspection" now finishes an active inspection instantly
- "Park Vehicles" now applies instantly to vehicles already in a service procedure
- Cold and overheating warnings for the engine/transmission now appear once instead of repeating constantly
- Vehicles now warn about extreme load through dashboard indicators
- Reworked dashboard indicator logic and added an activation sound
- Added an option to disable all warning messages
- Fixed multiplayer synchronization of engine and CVT temperature with the engine turned off
- Fixed battery capacity setting changes causing mass battery discharge
- Fixed repaired breakdown count in the maintenance log
- Fixed chained service procedures causing unintended repaint and repaint charges
- Fixed AutoDrive AI ignoring critical breakdowns
- Minor UI fixes

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Added compatibility with CVT Addon
- Expanded the in-game adjustment ranges for service interval and vehicle lifespan settings
- Scaled breakdown progression and other time-based mechanics to match custom service intervals and extended vehicle lifespans
- Fixed operating hours synchronization in multiplayer
- Fixed service interval progress calculation during initial vehicle initialization
- Added Polish and Spanish translations
- Minor UI fixes

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Increased interaction and connection distances for jumper cables
- Implemented a filter for system wear and stress accumulation that dampens sustained high-value factors while allowing short impulses to pass through
- Added new configuration options and expanded the adjustment ranges for existing ones
- Rebalanced wear factor multipliers (generally reduced for better gameplay balance)

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Reworked stress accumulation: stress can no longer exceed the current condition level of its system. When stress reaches condition, a breakdown occurs instantly
- Returning leased ADS vehicles now applies penalties for active breakdowns and overdue maintenance. Compatible with Extended Leasing
- Fixed: lubrication on harvesting vehicles now decays correctly instead of always staying at a normal level
- Fixed: harvesting activity is now detected correctly for work process wear calculations and for checking the presence of large debris
- Radiator and air intake clogging speed is now tied to the selected service interval length, allowing better adaptation to different gameplay styles
- Removed the long harvest factor from the work process system
- Reworked the fuel system's High Pressure Factor: it is now triggered by high fuel consumption instead of indirect engine load
- Fixed incorrect data display in the maintenance log and inspection report
- ADS now controls the vanilla engine temperature value
- Fixed a bug where the battery could discharge too quickly when AI tried to start a vehicle while ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER was active. As a temporary solution, AI is immune to ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS now controls operating hour accumulation for ADS vehicles, so hours continue to accumulate even when the player leaves the engine running

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Added multiplayer support
- Reworked the vehicle condition model: overall condition is now built from multiple individual systems, each with its own condition and wear factors
- Added a new stress system that accumulates stress in vehicle systems when machinery is used improperly, increasing breakdown risk
- Added an advanced battery and alternator simulation
- Added pre-shift vehicle inspection
- Added new shop items: Grease Gun, Air Blower, and Jumper Cables for pre-shift service and jump-starting vehicles with a discharged battery
- Added a fleet management table with all ADS vehicles for easier overview and control
- Added many new breakdowns and reworked existing ones; breakdowns now have strict assignment to specific systems
- Added a breakdown selection system that chooses failures based on which system factors were stressed or violated the most
- Added new workshop options and reworked existing service and repair flows
- Changed the hard engine start logic: the starter must now be held to crank the engine
- Numerous minor balance and interface improvements]]></en>

        <es><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System añade a Farming Simulator 25 un sistema profundo de desgaste, averías, diagnóstico, mantenimiento y reparación de vehículos. En lugar de depender de un único valor genérico de estado, cada máquina se compone de varios sistemas individuales con su propia condición, factores de desgaste, acumulación de estrés y riesgo de fallo. El comportamiento del vehículo y la naturaleza de las averías dependen de las condiciones de trabajo, la carga, la temperatura y la calidad del mantenimiento.

El mod incluye un modelo térmico para los sistemas principales, una simulación avanzada de batería y alternador, una lógica de averías realista, flujos de trabajo ampliados en el taller, informes de servicio, historial de mantenimiento e inspecciones previas al turno. Como resultado, la gestión de los vehículos se convierte en una parte estratégica de la jugabilidad: el mantenimiento lleva tiempo, el uso incorrecto aumenta el riesgo de fallos y descuidar el estado de la maquinaria puede interrumpir trabajos de campo importantes. Un agricultor responsable que cuide su equipo, lo mantenga a tiempo y evite abusos innecesarios mantendrá una flota fiable y evitará problemas graves durante la temporada.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Reequilibrados los factores de desgaste de los sistemas
- "Inspección rápida" ahora completa al instante una inspección activa
- "Aparcar vehículos" ahora se aplica al instante a los vehículos que ya están en servicio
- Las advertencias de motor/transmisión fríos o sobrecalentados ahora aparecen una sola vez en lugar de repetirse constantemente
- Ahora los vehículos avisan de cargas extremas mediante indicadores en el panel
- Se ha rediseñado la lógica de los indicadores del panel y se ha añadido un sonido de activación
- Añadida una opción para desactivar todos los mensajes de advertencia
- Corregida la sincronización en multijugador de la temperatura del motor y del CVT con el motor apagado
- Corregido un problema por el que cambiar la capacidad de la batería provocaba una descarga masiva de baterías
- Corregido el recuento de averías reparadas en el maintenance log
- Corregido un repintado no deseado y su coste al encadenar procedimientos de servicio
- Corregido que la IA de AutoDrive ignorara averías críticas
- Pequeñas correcciones de interfaz

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Añadida compatibilidad con CVT Addon
- Ampliados los rangos de ajuste del intervalo de servicio y de la vida útil del vehículo en la configuración
- Ajustada la progresión de averías y otras mecánicas basadas en el tiempo para adaptarse a intervalos de servicio personalizados y a vidas útiles extendidas
- Corregida la sincronización de las horas de funcionamiento en multijugador
- Corregido el cálculo del progreso del intervalo de servicio durante la inicialización del vehículo
- Añadidos los idiomas polaco y español
- Pequeñas correcciones de interfaz

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Aumentadas las distancias de interacción y conexión de los cables de arranque
- Implementado un filtro para el desgaste de los sistemas y la acumulación de estrés, que atenúa los factores elevados sostenidos mientras permite el paso de impulsos breves
- Añadidas nuevas opciones de configuración y ampliados los rangos de ajuste de las ya existentes
- Reequilibrados los multiplicadores de los factores de desgaste, generalmente reducidos para un mejor equilibrio de la jugabilidad

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Se ha rediseñado la acumulación de estrés: el estrés ya no puede superar el nivel de condición actual de su sistema. Cuando el estrés alcanza la condición, se produce una avería al instante
- La devolución de vehículos ADS en leasing ahora aplica penalizaciones por averías activas y mantenimiento atrasado. Compatible con Extended Leasing
- Corregido: la lubricación de las máquinas de cosecha ahora se degrada correctamente en lugar de permanecer siempre en un nivel normal
- Corregido: la actividad de cosecha ahora se detecta correctamente para los cálculos de desgaste del sistema de trabajo y para comprobar la presencia de residuos grandes
- La velocidad de obstrucción del radiador y de la admisión de aire ahora está vinculada a la duración del intervalo de servicio seleccionado, lo que permite una mejor adaptación a diferentes estilos de juego
- Se eliminó el factor de cosecha prolongada del sistema de proceso de trabajo
- Se ha rediseñado el factor de alta presión del sistema de combustible: ahora se activa por alto consumo de combustible en lugar de por carga indirecta del motor
- Corregida la visualización incorrecta de datos en el registro de mantenimiento y en el informe de inspección
- ADS ahora controla el valor vanilla de la temperatura del motor
- Corregido un error por el que la batería podía descargarse demasiado rápido cuando la IA intentaba arrancar un vehículo con ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER activo. Como solución temporal, la IA es inmune a ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS ahora controla la acumulación de horas de funcionamiento de los vehículos ADS, por lo que las horas siguen acumulándose incluso cuando el jugador deja el motor en marcha

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Añadido soporte multijugador
- Rediseñado el modelo de condición del vehículo: la condición general ahora se compone de varios sistemas individuales, cada uno con su propia condición y factores de desgaste
- Añadido un nuevo sistema de estrés que acumula estrés en los sistemas del vehículo cuando la maquinaria se utiliza de forma incorrecta, aumentando el riesgo de avería
- Añadida una simulación avanzada de batería y alternador
- Añadida la inspección del vehículo antes del turno
- Añadidos nuevos objetos de tienda: pistola de engrase, soplador de aire y cables de arranque para el servicio previo al turno y el arranque de vehículos con la batería descargada
- Añadida una tabla de gestión de flota con todos los vehículos ADS para facilitar la supervisión y el control
- Añadidas muchas averías nuevas y revisadas las existentes; las averías ahora están asignadas estrictamente a sistemas concretos
- Añadido un sistema de selección de averías que elige los fallos según qué factores del sistema hayan sido más estresados o vulnerados
- Añadidas nuevas opciones de taller y revisados los flujos de mantenimiento y reparación existentes
- Cambiada la lógica de arranque difícil del motor: ahora es necesario mantener pulsado el arranque para hacer girar el motor
- Numerosas mejoras menores de equilibrio e interfaz]]></es>

         <pl><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System dodaje do gry Farming Simulator 25 rozbudowany system zużycia pojazdów, awarii, diagnostyki, konserwacji i napraw. Zamiast polegać na jednej, ogólnej wartości stanu, każda maszyna jest zbudowana wokół wielu indywidualnych systemów, posiadających własny stan, czynniki zużycia, akumulację naprężeń i ryzyko awarii. Zachowanie pojazdu i charakter usterek zależą od warunków eksploatacji, obciążenia, temperatury i jakości serwisu.

Modyfikacja zawiera model temperatury kluczowych systemów, zaawansowaną symulację akumulatora i alternatora, realistyczną logikę awarii, rozszerzone przepływy pracy w warsztacie, raporty serwisowe, historię konserwacji oraz inspekcje przedrozruchowe. W rezultacie zarządzanie pojazdami staje się strategiczną częścią rozgrywki: serwis zajmuje czas, złe użytkowanie zwiększa ryzyko awarii, a zaniedbanie stanu maszyny może zakłócić krytyczne prace polowe. Odpowiedzialny rolnik, który dba o sprzęt, serwisuje go na czas i unika niepotrzebnego nadużywania, utrzyma flotę w niezawodnym stanie i uniknie poważnych problemów w trakcie sezonu.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Zbalansowano czynniki zużycia systemów
- „Szybka inspekcja” teraz natychmiast kończy aktywną inspekcję
- „Parkuj pojazdy” teraz natychmiast działa na pojazdy już będące w procedurze serwisowej
- Ostrzeżenia o zimnym lub przegrzanym silniku/skrzyni pojawiają się teraz tylko raz zamiast powtarzać się bez końca
- Pojazdy ostrzegają teraz o ekstremalnym obciążeniu za pomocą wskaźników na desce rozdzielczej
- Przeprojektowano logikę wskaźników na desce rozdzielczej i dodano dźwięk aktywacji
- Dodano opcję wyłączenia wszystkich komunikatów ostrzegawczych
- Naprawiono synchronizację temperatury silnika i CVT w trybie wieloosobowym przy zgaszonym silniku
- Naprawiono problem, przez który zmiana pojemności akumulatora powodowała masowe rozładowanie baterii
- Naprawiono liczenie usuniętych awarii w maintenance log
- Naprawiono nieplanowane malowanie i opłaty za malowanie przy łączeniu procedur serwisowych
- Naprawiono ignorowanie krytycznych awarii przez AutoDrive AI
- Drobne poprawki interfejsu

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Dodano kompatybilność z CVT Addon
- Rozszerzono zakresy regulacji interwału serwisowego i żywotności pojazdu w ustawieniach
- Dostosowano progresję awarii i inne mechaniki zależne od czasu do niestandardowych interwałów serwisowych i wydłużonej żywotności pojazdu
- Naprawiono synchronizację godzin pracy w trybie wieloosobowym
- Naprawiono obliczanie postępu interwału serwisowego podczas inicjalizacji pojazdu
- Dodano tłumaczenia polskie i hiszpańskie
- Drobne poprawki interfejsu

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Zwiększono odległości interakcji i połączenia dla kabli rozruchowych
- Zaimplementowano filtr dla zużycia systemów i akumulacji naprężeń, który tłumi długotrwałe wysokie wartości, jednocześnie pozwalając na przejście krótkich impulsów
- Dodano nowe opcje konfiguracji i rozszerzono zakresy regulacji dla istniejących
- Zbalansowano mnożniki czynnika zużycia (ogólnie zmniejszone dla lepszego balansu rozgrywki)

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Przeprojektowano akumulację naprężeń: naprężenia nie mogą już przekraczać aktualnego poziomu stanu swojego systemu. Gdy naprężenie osiągnie stan, awaria następuje natychmiast
- Zwrot wynajętych pojazdów ADS nakłada kary za aktywne awarie i przeterminowaną konserwację. Kompatybilne z Extended Leasing
- Naprawiono: smarowanie w pojazdach żniwnych teraz prawidłowo się zużywa, zamiast zawsze pozostawać na normalnym poziomie
- Naprawiono: aktywność żniwna jest teraz prawidłowo wykrywana do obliczeń zużycia procesu roboczego i do sprawdzania obecności dużych zanieczyszczeń
- Prędkość zatykania chłodnicy i wlotu powietrza jest teraz powiązana z wybraną długością interwału serwisowego, co pozwala na lepsze dostosowanie do różnych stylów gry
- Usunięto długi czynnik żniwny z systemu procesu roboczego
- Przeprojektowano czynnik wysokiego ciśnienia w układzie paliwowym: jest on teraz wyzwalany przez wysokie zużycie paliwa zamiast pośredniego obciążenia silnika
- Naprawiono nieprawidłowe wyświetlanie danych w dzienniku konserwacji i raporcie z inspekcji
- ADS steruje teraz wartością temperatury silnika z gry podstawowej
- Naprawiono błąd, w którym akumulator mógł się zbyt szybko rozładować, gdy SI próbowała uruchomić pojazd, podczas gdy aktywny był ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER. Jako tymczasowe rozwiązanie, SI jest odporna na ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS steruje teraz akumulacją godzin pracy dla pojazdów ADS, więc godziny nadal się naliczają, nawet gdy gracz pozostawia silnik włączony

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Dodano wsparcie dla trybu wieloosobowego
- Przeprojektowano model stanu pojazdu: ogólny stan jest teraz budowany z wielu indywidualnych systemów, każdy z własnym stanem i czynnikami zużycia
- Dodano nowy system naprężeń, który akumuluje naprężenia w systemach pojazdu podczas niewłaściwego użytkowania maszyn, zwiększając ryzyko awarii
- Dodano zaawansowaną symulację akumulatora i alternatora
- Dodano inspekcję pojazdu przed rozruchem
- Dodano nowe przedmioty w warsztacie: Pistolet do smarowania, Dmuchawa powietrza i Kable rozruchowe do serwisu przedrozruchowego i uruchamiania pojazdów z rozładowanym akumulatorem
- Dodano tabelę zarządzania flotą ze wszystkimi pojazdami ADS dla łatwiejszego przeglądu i kontroli
- Dodano wiele nowych awarii i przeprojektowano istniejące; awarie są teraz ściśle przypisane do konkretnych systemów
- Dodano system wyboru awarii, który wybiera usterki w oparciu o to, które czynniki systemowe były najbardziej obciążone lub naruszone
- Dodano nowe opcje warsztatowe i przeprojektowano istniejące przepływy serwisu i napraw
- Zmieniono logikę trudnego rozruchu silnika: rozrusznik musi być teraz przytrzymany, aby uruchomić silnik
- Liczne drobne ulepszenia balansu i interfejsu]]></pl>

        <de><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System fügt Farming Simulator 25 ein tiefgehendes System für Verschleiß, Ausfälle, Diagnose, Wartung und Reparatur von Fahrzeugen hinzu. Anstelle eines einzigen allgemeinen Zustandswerts besteht jede Maschine aus mehreren einzelnen Systemen mit eigenem Zustand, eigenen Verschleißfaktoren, Stressaufbau und Ausfallrisiko. Fahrverhalten und Art der Defekte hängen von Einsatzbedingungen, Belastung, Temperatur und Wartungsqualität ab.

Der Mod umfasst ein Temperaturmodell für wichtige Systeme, eine erweiterte Batterie- und Lichtmaschinensimulation, realistische Ausfalllogik, erweiterte Werkstattabläufe, Serviceberichte, Wartungshistorie und Vorschicht-Inspektionen. Dadurch wird Fahrzeugmanagement zu einem strategischen Teil des Gameplays: Wartung kostet Zeit, falscher Einsatz erhöht das Ausfallrisiko, und vernachlässigter Maschinenzustand kann wichtige Feldarbeiten gefährden. Ein verantwortungsvoller Landwirt, der seine Technik pflegt, rechtzeitig wartet und unnötige Überlastung vermeidet, hält seinen Fuhrpark zuverlässig und vermeidet ernsthafte Probleme in der Saison.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Die Verschleißfaktoren der Systeme wurden neu ausbalanciert
- „Schnelle Inspektion“ beendet eine laufende Inspektion jetzt sofort
- „Fahrzeuge parken“ wirkt jetzt sofort auf Fahrzeuge, die sich bereits in einem Servicevorgang befinden
- Warnungen bei kaltem oder überhitztem Motor/Getriebe erscheinen jetzt nur noch einmal statt sich ständig zu wiederholen
- Fahrzeuge warnen nun über Anzeigen im Armaturenbrett bei extremer Belastung
- Die Logik der Armaturenbrettanzeigen wurde überarbeitet und um einen Aktivierungston ergänzt
- Es wurde eine Option zum Deaktivieren aller Warnmeldungen hinzugefügt
- Die Synchronisierung von Motor- und CVT-Temperatur im Mehrspielermodus bei abgestelltem Motor wurde behoben
- Ein Fehler wurde behoben, durch den Änderungen der Batteriekapazität eine Massenentladung aller Batterien auslösen konnten
- Die Zählung behobener Defekte im maintenance log wurde korrigiert
- Ungeplante Lackierung und Lackierkosten bei verketteten Servicevorgängen wurden behoben
- Es wurde behoben, dass AutoDrive-KI kritische Defekte ignoriert
- Kleinere UI-Verbesserungen

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Kompatibilität mit CVT Addon hinzugefügt
- Die Einstellbereiche für Serviceintervall und Fahrzeuglebensdauer im Spiel wurden erweitert
- Die Progression von Pannen und anderen zeitbasierten Mechaniken wurde an benutzerdefinierte Serviceintervalle und verlängerte Fahrzeuglebensdauer angepasst
- Die Synchronisierung der Betriebsstunden im Mehrspielermodus wurde behoben
- Die Berechnung des Fortschritts des Serviceintervalls bei der Fahrzeuginitialisierung wurde behoben
- Polnische und spanische Übersetzungen hinzugefügt
- Kleinere UI-Verbesserungen

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Interaktions- und Verbindungsdistanzen für Starthilfekabel wurden erhöht
- Ein Filter für Systemverschleiß und Stressaufbau wurde implementiert, der anhaltend hohe Faktoren dämpft, während kurze Impulse weiterhin durchgelassen werden
- Neue Konfigurationsoptionen wurden hinzugefügt und die Einstellbereiche bestehender Optionen erweitert
- Multiplikatoren für Verschleißfaktoren wurden neu ausbalanciert und für ein besseres Gameplay insgesamt reduziert

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Die Stressakkumulation wurde überarbeitet: Stress kann nun den aktuellen Zustandswert des jeweiligen Systems nicht mehr überschreiten. Erreicht der Stress den Zustandswert, tritt sofort eine Panne auf
- Bei der Rückgabe geleaster ADS-Fahrzeuge werden nun Strafkosten für aktive Defekte und überfällige Wartung berechnet. Kompatibel mit Extended Leasing
- Behoben: Die Schmierung von Erntemaschinen nimmt jetzt korrekt ab, statt dauerhaft auf normalem Niveau zu bleiben
- Behoben: Ernteaktivität wird nun korrekt für die Berechnung des Verschleißes im Arbeitssystem und für die Erkennung von grobem Schmutz erfasst
- Die Verschmutzungsgeschwindigkeit von Kühler und Lufteinlass ist nun an das gewählte Wartungsintervall gekoppelt, um unterschiedliche Spielstile besser zu unterstützen
- Der Long-Harvest-Faktor wurde aus dem Arbeitssystem entfernt
- Der High Pressure Factor des Kraftstoffsystems wurde überarbeitet: Er wird nun durch hohen Kraftstoffverbrauch statt durch indirekte Motorlast ausgelöst
- Fehlerhafte Datenanzeige im Wartungsprotokoll und im Inspektionsbericht wurde behoben
- ADS steuert jetzt den Vanilla-Wert der Motortemperatur
- Ein Fehler wurde behoben, bei dem sich die Batterie zu schnell entladen konnte, wenn die KI bei aktivem ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER versuchte, ein Fahrzeug zu starten. Als vorläufige Lösung ist die KI gegen ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER immun
- ADS steuert jetzt die Erfassung der Betriebsstunden für ADS-Fahrzeuge, sodass sie weiterlaufen, auch wenn der Spieler das Fahrzeug mit laufendem Motor verlässt

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Mehrspieler-Unterstützung hinzugefügt
- Das Zustandsmodell der Fahrzeuge wurde überarbeitet: Der Gesamtzustand basiert nun auf mehreren einzelnen Systemen mit eigenem Zustand und eigenen Verschleißfaktoren
- Neues Stresssystem hinzugefügt: Bei falscher Nutzung sammeln die Fahrzeugsysteme Belastung an, wodurch das Ausfallrisiko steigt
- Erweiterte Simulation von Batterie und Lichtmaschine hinzugefügt
- Vorschicht-Inspektion für Fahrzeuge hinzugefügt
- Neue Shop-Gegenstände hinzugefügt: Fettpresse, Luftgebläse und Starthilfekabel für Vorschicht-Service und Starthilfe bei entladener Batterie
- Eine Flottenübersicht mit allen ADS-Fahrzeugen für eine einfachere Verwaltung hinzugefügt
- Viele neue Pannen hinzugefügt und bestehende überarbeitet; Ausfälle sind nun klar einzelnen Systemen zugeordnet
- Ein neues System zur Auswahl von Pannen hinzugefügt, das Defekte danach bestimmt, welche Systemfaktoren am stärksten belastet oder verletzt wurden
- Neue Werkstattoptionen hinzugefügt und bestehende Service- und Reparaturabläufe überarbeitet
- Die Logik des erschwerten Motorstarts geändert: Der Anlasser muss nun gehalten werden, um den Motor durchzudrehen
- Zahlreiche kleinere Balance- und Interface-Verbesserungen]]></de>
        <fr><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System ajoute à Farming Simulator 25 un système approfondi d'usure, de pannes, de diagnostic, d'entretien et de réparation des véhicules. Au lieu de reposer sur une seule valeur générale d'état, chaque machine est composée de plusieurs systèmes distincts ayant leur propre état, leurs propres facteurs d'usure, leur accumulation de stress et leur risque de panne. Le comportement de la machine et la nature des défaillances dépendent des conditions d'utilisation, de la charge, de la température et de la qualité de l'entretien.

Le mod comprend un modèle thermique pour les systèmes clés, une simulation avancée de la batterie et de l'alternateur, une logique de pannes réaliste, des procédures d'atelier étendues, des rapports d'intervention, un historique d'entretien et des inspections avant prise de poste. La gestion du matériel devient ainsi une dimension stratégique du gameplay : l'entretien prend du temps, une mauvaise utilisation augmente le risque de panne, et négliger l'état des machines peut compromettre des travaux de campagne essentiels. Un agriculteur consciencieux qui surveille son matériel, l'entretient à temps et évite les mauvais traitements inutiles conservera une flotte fiable et évitera de graves problèmes en saison.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Rééquilibrage des facteurs d'usure des systèmes
- « Inspection rapide » termine désormais instantanément une inspection en cours
- « Garer les véhicules » s'applique désormais instantanément aux véhicules déjà engagés dans une procédure d'entretien
- Les avertissements de moteur/transmission froids ou en surchauffe n'apparaissent désormais qu'une seule fois au lieu de se répéter en permanence
- Les véhicules avertissent désormais d'une charge extrême via les indicateurs du tableau de bord
- La logique des indicateurs du tableau de bord a été retravaillée et un son d'activation a été ajouté
- Ajout d'une option pour désactiver tous les messages d'avertissement
- Correction de la synchronisation multijoueur des températures moteur et CVT lorsque le moteur est coupé
- Correction d'un problème où le changement de capacité de batterie provoquait une décharge massive de toutes les batteries
- Correction du comptage des pannes réparées dans le maintenance log
- Correction d'une repeinture involontaire et de son coût lors de l'enchaînement de procédures d'entretien
- Correction du problème où l'IA d'AutoDrive ignorait les pannes critiques
- Corrections mineures de l'interface

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Ajout de la compatibilité avec CVT Addon
- Extension des plages de réglage de l'intervalle d'entretien et de la durée de vie des véhicules dans les paramètres
- Ajustement de la progression des pannes et des autres mécaniques basées sur le temps aux intervalles d'entretien personnalisés et aux durées de vie prolongées des véhicules
- Correction de la synchronisation des heures de fonctionnement en multijoueur
- Correction du calcul de la progression de l'intervalle d'entretien lors de l'initialisation du véhicule
- Ajout des traductions polonaise et espagnole
- Corrections mineures de l'interface

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Augmentation des distances d'interaction et de connexion des câbles de démarrage
- Mise en place d'un filtre pour l'usure des systèmes et l'accumulation de stress, qui atténue les facteurs élevés durables tout en laissant passer les impulsions courtes
- Ajout de nouvelles options de configuration et extension des plages de réglage des options existantes
- Rééquilibrage des multiplicateurs des facteurs d'usure, globalement réduits pour un meilleur équilibre de jeu

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Refonte de l'accumulation de stress : le stress ne peut désormais plus dépasser le niveau de condition actuel de son système. Lorsque le stress atteint la condition, une panne survient instantanément
- Le retour des véhicules ADS en leasing applique désormais des pénalités pour les pannes actives et l'entretien en retard. Compatible avec Extended Leasing
- Correction : la lubrification des machines de récolte diminue désormais correctement au lieu de rester en permanence à un niveau normal
- Correction : l'activité de récolte est maintenant détectée correctement pour les calculs d'usure du système de travail et pour la détection de gros débris
- La vitesse d'encrassement du radiateur et de l'admission d'air est désormais liée à la durée de l'intervalle d'entretien sélectionné, pour mieux s'adapter aux différents styles de jeu
- Suppression du facteur long harvest du système de travail
- Refonte du High Pressure Factor du système de carburant : il se déclenche désormais en fonction d'une forte consommation de carburant plutôt que d'une charge moteur indirecte
- Correction d'un affichage incorrect des données dans le journal d'entretien et le rapport d'inspection
- ADS contrôle désormais la valeur vanilla de la température moteur
- Correction d'un bug où la batterie pouvait se décharger trop rapidement lorsque l'IA tentait de démarrer un véhicule avec ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER actif. Comme solution temporaire, l'IA est immunisée contre ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS contrôle désormais l'accumulation des heures de fonctionnement pour les véhicules ADS, afin qu'elles continuent à s'accumuler même lorsque le joueur quitte un véhicule avec le moteur en marche

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Ajout du support multijoueur
- Refonte du modèle d'état des véhicules : l'état global repose désormais sur plusieurs systèmes distincts, chacun avec son propre état et ses propres facteurs d'usure
- Ajout d'un nouveau système de stress : une mauvaise utilisation augmente la charge des systèmes et le risque de panne
- Ajout d'une simulation avancée de la batterie et de l'alternateur
- Ajout de l'inspection visuelle avant prise de poste
- Ajout de nouveaux objets en boutique : pompe à graisse, souffleur d'air et câbles de démarrage pour l'entretien avant service et le démarrage d'un véhicule à batterie déchargée
- Ajout d'un tableau de gestion regroupant tous les véhicules ADS pour un suivi plus pratique
- Ajout de nombreuses nouvelles pannes et refonte des anciennes ; chaque panne est désormais strictement rattachée à un système précis
- Ajout d'un système de sélection des pannes qui choisit les défaillances en fonction des facteurs de système les plus sollicités ou les plus perturbés
- Ajout de nouvelles options d'atelier et refonte des anciens flux d'entretien et de réparation
- Modification de la logique de démarrage difficile du moteur : il faut désormais maintenir le démarreur pour lancer le moteur
- De nombreuses améliorations mineures d'équilibrage et d'interface]]></fr>

        <it><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System aggiunge a Farming Simulator 25 un sistema approfondito di usura, guasti, diagnostica, manutenzione e riparazione dei veicoli. Invece di basarsi su un unico valore generico di condizione, ogni macchina è composta da più sistemi separati con la propria condizione, i propri fattori di usura, accumulo di stress e rischio di guasto. Il comportamento del veicolo e la natura dei guasti dipendono dalle condizioni operative, dal carico, dalla temperatura e dalla qualità della manutenzione.

Il mod include un modello termico per i sistemi principali, una simulazione avanzata di batteria e alternatore, una logica dei guasti realistica, procedure d'officina ampliate, rapporti di servizio, storico della manutenzione e ispezioni pre-turno. Di conseguenza, la gestione dei veicoli diventa una parte strategica del gameplay: la manutenzione richiede tempo, l'uso scorretto aumenta il rischio di guasti e trascurare lo stato delle macchine può compromettere lavori agricoli importanti. Un agricoltore responsabile che si prende cura dei mezzi, li manutiene in tempo ed evita abusi inutili manterrà la flotta affidabile ed eviterà problemi seri durante la stagione.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Ribilanciati i fattori di usura dei sistemi
- “Ispezione rapida” ora completa immediatamente un'ispezione attiva
- “Parcheggia veicoli” ora si applica immediatamente ai veicoli già coinvolti in una procedura di assistenza
- Gli avvisi di motore/trasmissione freddi o surriscaldati ora compaiono una sola volta invece di ripetersi continuamente
- I veicoli avvisano ora di carichi estremi tramite gli indicatori sul cruscotto
- La logica degli indicatori del cruscotto è stata rielaborata ed è stato aggiunto un suono di attivazione
- Aggiunta un'opzione per disattivare tutti i messaggi di avviso
- Corretta la sincronizzazione multigiocatore delle temperature di motore e CVT a motore spento
- Corretto un problema per cui la modifica della capacità della batteria causava lo scaricamento massivo di tutte le batterie
- Corretto il conteggio dei guasti riparati nel maintenance log
- Corretta la verniciatura involontaria e il relativo costo nelle procedure di assistenza concatenate
- Corretto il problema per cui l'IA di AutoDrive ignorava i guasti critici
- Piccole correzioni all'interfaccia

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Aggiunta la compatibilità con CVT Addon
- Estesi gli intervalli di regolazione dell'intervallo di manutenzione e della vita utile del veicolo nelle impostazioni
- Adattata la progressione dei guasti e delle altre meccaniche basate sul tempo agli intervalli di manutenzione personalizzati e alla maggiore vita utile dei veicoli
- Corretta la sincronizzazione delle ore di funzionamento in multigiocatore
- Corretto il calcolo del progresso dell'intervallo di manutenzione durante l'inizializzazione del veicolo
- Aggiunte le traduzioni polacca e spagnola
- Piccole correzioni all'interfaccia

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Aumentate le distanze di interazione e collegamento dei cavi di avviamento
- Implementato un filtro per l'usura dei sistemi e l'accumulo di stress che attenua i fattori elevati prolungati lasciando però passare gli impulsi brevi
- Aggiunte nuove opzioni di configurazione ed estesi gli intervalli di regolazione di quelle esistenti
- Ribilanciati i moltiplicatori dei fattori di usura, generalmente ridotti per un miglior bilanciamento del gameplay

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Rivisto il sistema di accumulo dello stress: lo stress non può più superare il livello di condizione attuale del proprio sistema. Quando lo stress raggiunge la condizione, il guasto si verifica immediatamente
- La restituzione dei veicoli ADS in leasing applica ora penali per i guasti attivi e per la manutenzione scaduta. Compatibile con Extended Leasing
- Corretto: la lubrificazione delle macchine da raccolta ora diminuisce correttamente invece di restare sempre a un livello normale
- Corretto: l'attività di raccolta viene ora rilevata correttamente per i calcoli di usura del sistema di lavoro e per il controllo della presenza di detriti di grandi dimensioni
- La velocità di intasamento del radiatore e della presa d'aria è ora collegata alla durata dell'intervallo di manutenzione selezionato, per adattarsi meglio ai diversi stili di gioco
- Rimosso il fattore long harvest dal sistema di lavoro
- Rivisto l'High Pressure Factor del sistema di alimentazione: ora si attiva in base all'elevato consumo di carburante invece che al carico motore indiretto
- Corretta la visualizzazione errata dei dati nel registro di manutenzione e nel report di ispezione
- ADS ora controlla il valore vanilla della temperatura motore
- Corretto un bug per cui la batteria poteva scaricarsi troppo rapidamente quando l'IA tentava di avviare un veicolo con ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER attivo. Come soluzione temporanea, l'IA è immune a ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS ora controlla l'accumulo delle ore di funzionamento per i veicoli ADS, così le ore continuano ad accumularsi anche quando il giocatore lascia il motore acceso

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Aggiunto supporto multigiocatore
- Rivisto il modello delle condizioni del veicolo: la condizione generale ora dipende da più sistemi separati, ognuno con la propria condizione e i propri fattori di usura
- Aggiunto un nuovo sistema di stress: l'uso improprio accumula stress nei sistemi del veicolo e aumenta il rischio di guasti
- Aggiunta una simulazione avanzata di batteria e alternatore
- Aggiunta l'ispezione pre-turno del veicolo
- Aggiunti nuovi oggetti nel negozio: ingrassatore, soffiatore d'aria e cavi di avviamento per il servizio pre-turno e l'avviamento di veicoli con batteria scarica
- Aggiunta una tabella di gestione con tutti i veicoli ADS per un controllo più comodo del parco mezzi
- Aggiunti numerosi nuovi guasti e rivisti quelli esistenti; ora ogni guasto appartiene in modo preciso a un sistema specifico
- Aggiunto un sistema di selezione dei guasti che determina le avarie in base ai fattori di sistema maggiormente stressati o compromessi
- Aggiunte nuove opzioni d'officina e rivisti i flussi esistenti di manutenzione e riparazione
- Modificata la logica di avviamento difficile del motore: ora il motorino di avviamento deve essere tenuto premuto per far girare il motore
- Numerose piccole modifiche al bilanciamento e all'interfaccia]]></it>

        <ru><![CDATA[Advanced Damage System добавляет в Farming Simulator 25 глубокую систему износа, поломок, диагностики, обслуживания и ремонта техники. Вместо одного условного параметра состояния каждая машина состоит из отдельных систем, каждая из которых имеет собственный уровень состояния, факторы износа, накопление стресса и риск отказа. Поведение техники и характер поломок зависят от условий эксплуатации, нагрузки, температуры и качества обслуживания.

Мод включает температурную модель ключевых систем, продвинутую симуляцию аккумулятора и генератора, реалистичную логику поломок, расширенные сценарии работы с мастерской, сервисные отчёты, журнал обслуживания и возможность проведения предсменного осмотра. В результате техника требует не только ремонта, но и грамотного планирования: обслуживание занимает время, неправильная эксплуатация повышает риск отказов, а пренебрежение состоянием машин может сорвать важные полевые работы. Ответственный фермер, который следит за техникой, вовремя обслуживает её и не работает на пределе возможностей без необходимости, сможет сохранить парк в надёжном состоянии и избежать серьёзных проблем в сезон.

Changelog 0.9.2.0:
- Перебалансированы факторы износа систем
- «Быстрый осмотр» теперь мгновенно завершает активный осмотр
- «Парковать технику» теперь мгновенно применяется к технике, уже находящейся в сервисной процедуре
- Предупреждения о холодном или перегретом двигателе/трансмиссии теперь появляются один раз вместо постоянного повторения
- Теперь техника предупреждает об экстремальной нагрузке через индикацию на приборной панели
- Логика индикации на приборной панели переработана, добавлен звук активации
- Добавлена возможность отключить все предупреждающие сообщения
- Исправлена синхронизация температуры двигателя и CVT в мультиплеере при заглушенном двигателе
- Исправлена ошибка, из-за которой изменение ёмкости батареи могло массово разрядить все аккумуляторы
- Исправлен подсчёт устранённых поломок в maintenance log
- Исправлены незапланированная перекраска и списание средств при цепочке сервисных процедур
- Исправлено игнорирование критических поломок ИИ AutoDrive
- Небольшие исправления интерфейса

Changelog 0.9.1.2:
- Добавлена совместимость с CVT Addon
- Расширены диапазоны регулировки сервисного интервала и ресурса техники в настройках
- Скорректирована прогрессия поломок и других механик, завязанных на время, под пользовательские значения сервисного интервала и ресурса техники
- Исправлена синхронизация моточасов в мультиплеере
- Исправлен расчёт прогресса сервисного интервала при инициализации техники
- Добавлены польский и испанский переводы
- Небольшие исправления интерфейса

Changelog 0.9.1.1:
- Увеличены дистанции взаимодействия и подключения для пусковых проводов
- Реализован фильтр износа систем и накопления стресса, который приглушает длительные высокие факторы, но пропускает кратковременные импульсы
- Добавлены новые настройки конфигурации и расширены диапазоны регулировки существующих параметров
- Перебалансированы множители факторов износа: в целом они были снижены для более комфортного игрового баланса

Changelog 0.9.1.0:
- Переработана система накопления стресса: стресс больше не может превышать текущий уровень состояния своей системы. Когда стресс достигает уровня состояния, поломка происходит мгновенно
- При возврате транспорта ADS, взятого в лизинг, теперь начисляются штрафы за активные поломки и просроченное ТО. Совместимо с модом Extended Leasing
- Исправлено: уровень смазки уборочной техники теперь корректно уменьшается, а не остаётся постоянно в норме
- Исправлено: активность уборки урожая теперь корректно определяется для расчётов износа рабочей системы и для проверки наличия крупного мусора
- Скорость загрязнения радиаторов и воздухозаборников теперь привязана к выбранной длительности сервисного интервала, чтобы лучше адаптироваться к разным стилям игры
- Удалён long harvest factor из системы work process
- Переработан High Pressure Factor в топливной системе: теперь он срабатывает от высокого расхода топлива, а не от косвенной загрузки двигателя
- Исправлено некорректное отображение данных в журнале обслуживания и в отчёте осмотра
- ADS теперь управляет ванильным значением температуры двигателя
- Исправлен баг, из-за которого аккумулятор мог слишком быстро разряжаться, когда ИИ пытался завести технику при активном эффекте ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER. В качестве временного решения ИИ имеет иммунитет к ENGINE_HARD_START_MODIFIER
- ADS теперь управляет начислением моточасов для своей техники, поэтому моточасы продолжают накапливаться, даже если игрок покинул технику с работающим двигателем

Changelog 0.9.0.0:
- Добавлена поддержка мультиплеера
- Полностью переработана модель состояния техники: теперь общее состояние формируется не одним параметром, а состоянием отдельных систем, каждая из которых имеет собственный уровень износа и свои факторы деградации
- Добавлена новая система стресса: при неправильной эксплуатации техника накапливает нагрузку по системам, что повышает вероятность поломок
- Добавлена продвинутая симуляция аккумулятора и генератора
- Добавлена возможность проведения предсменного осмотра техники
- В магазин добавлены новые предметы: Grease Gun, Air Blower, Jumper Cables для предсменного обслуживания и запуска техники с разряженным аккумулятором
- В меню добавлена таблица со всей техникой Advanced Damage System для более удобного управления парком
- Добавлено множество новых поломок, а существующие переработаны. Теперь каждая поломка имеет чёткую принадлежность к конкретной системе
- Добавлена новая логика выбора поломок: вероятность их возникновения теперь зависит от того, какие факторы износа и нагрузки были сильнее всего нарушены в соответствующей системе
- Добавлены новые опции мастерской, а существующие варианты обслуживания и ремонта переработаны
- Изменена логика сложного запуска двигателя: теперь для запуска стартер необходимо удерживать, имитируя реальную прокрутку двигателя
- Многочисленные минорные изменения в балансе и интерфейсе]]></ru>
        
    </description>
    <storeItems>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="objects/greaseGun/greaseGun.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="objects/airBlower/airBlower.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="objects/jumperCables/jumperCables.xml"/>
    </storeItems>
    <iconFilename>icon_ads.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/ADS_Main.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
    <actions>
        <action name="ADS_FIELD_INSPECTION" axisType="HALF" displayCategory="PLAYER_INTERACTIVE"/>
    </actions>
    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="ADS_FIELD_INSPECTION">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_r"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>
    <l10n filenamePrefix="translations/l10n"/>
    <dependencies>
        <dependency>FS25_Vehicle_Years</dependency>
    </dependencies>
</modDesc>
